Ricky Kennedy

10 Ava Road, Ava Tower

Email: rickykennedy.development@gmail.com

Personal Particulars



Name : Ricky Kennedy (Mr)
Date of Birth : 24 August 1989

Citizenship : Indonesian

Race: Indonesian/Chinese

Gender : Male Marital Status : Single

Email : rickykennedy.development@gmail.com

Profile

Enthusiastic learner, willing to learn, honest, independent but also able to work in a team, resourceful and self-motivated to seek for improvement as I believe that no matter how good I am there are definitely more things that I need to learn. I am currently holding a diploma major in Business Application, that's looking for a full-time IT-related job to earn a stable income, experience and to improve his IT skills as well as contribute my skill and ability to help the company's growth and success. Previously I have worked in a startup company that developed web application for more than 2 years. After that I went for further studies to complete my degree in Bachelor of Computer Science major in Digital Systems Security. Currently working as a Mobile and Web Developer.

Career Experience

YellowCube Pte Ltd (Mobile & Web Developer) – Full Time (08/08/2016 – Present) Responsibilities:

- Build mobile application for iOS and android using Appcelerator
- Build web application/system using codeigniter (PHP) and javascript/jQuery
- Use twitter bootstrap for front-end framework
- Maintaining existing website
- Use HTML5 and responsive design to support different browsers and mobile
- Use git as a version control. In particular using bitbucket as a git hosting services.
- Gather and translate business requitements into application design and functionality
- Work with various stakeholders to plan the roll-out of application and subsequent enhancements.
- Evaluate and integrate new web and mobile app technologies to meet business/marketing needs

Epiphany Education (Web Developer) – Full Time (08/10/2012 – 30/11/2014) Responsibilities:

- Build web application using cakephp (PHP) and javascript/jQuery
- Use foundation for front-end framework
- Use available plugins and modify for specific purpose
- Use HTML5 and responsive design to support different browsers and mobile
- Use git as a versioning control
- Use css to beautify the web application

Internship (02/2011 - 04/2011)

Racer Technology Pte Ltd

Responsibilities:

- Using Microsoft Excel to managed their past goods record
- Checking of goods (Scraps or Fine goods)
- Manually sort their finance record

Skills & Knowledge

Technical Skills:

- Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)
- Using MYSQL Workbench to design database
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Python, PHP, HTML/ HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Object-Oriented Java
- Basic of SAP ERP(Systems, Applications, and Products)
- Backend Framework (CakePhp, CodeIgniter, Yii)
- Frontend Framework (Foundation, Twitter Bootstrap)
- Git for version control
- Java
- C++
- Appcelerator

Other skills:

- Good Presentation/Public Speaking Skill
- Team Management/ Team Player
- Good Interpersonal/Communication Skill
- Reading codes/plugins and modify if necessary

Basic Knowledge:

- Website Development & Deployment
- Basic OS Concepts for Windows
- Basic IT Security
- IT Project Management
- Object-Oriented Programming Concept
- Database System
- System Analysis and Design
- Micro-Economics
- Macro-Economics
- Banking and Finance Application
- Manufacturing and Logistics system
- Business Intelligence
- Human Resource Management

Education Background

2013 – 2016: University of Wollongong/ SIM (Bachelor in Computer Science major in Digital Systems Security)

2009 – 2012: Republic Polytechnic (Diploma in Business Application)

2005 – 2008: Mayflower Secondary School

Express Stream

➤ General Certificate of Education 'Ordinary' Level

2002 – 2004: SMPN 1 (Junior High School)

1996 – 2001: SDN 1 (Primary School)

Academic Awards & Achievements

2012:

- Involve in FYP and provide assistance for team
- Act as leader in One of the Final Year Project and help teammates in meeting deadline

2009 – 2012: Republic Polytechnic (Diploma in Business Application)

- Final Year Project 1 Twitter Exploratory (build twitter search engine in python)
- Final Year Project 2 Trainer Management System for one of the industrial partner

2005 – 2008: Mayflower Secondary School

- Member of Badminton Team and participate in Inter School Competition
- House leader for one of the 4 main houses and participate in Intra-School Activities
- Vice President of Peer Leader Board (07 &08)

Language Proficiency

English (Written and Spoken) Bahasa Melayu (Written and Spoken) Bahasa Indonesia (Written and Spoken)